Nandha Kumar

Software Engineer

Summary:

Motivated Software engineering graduate with 3+ years of experience in analyze, design, development of software development. Seeking for an opportunity to work in a challenging environment to prove my skills and utilize my intelligence in the growth of the organization.

Work experience:

Infosys, India.

Senior software engineer

Dec 2020 - July 2021

- Successfully led technical Core team, to Migrate the middleware layer from IBM BPM to RedHat camel framework, deployed on JBoss fuse.
- Engineered Microservices using Spring boot java on Apache camel and testing was done with postman and Karate.
- Deployed the interface successfully in PROD using OpenShift and GitLab in (CICD) continuous integration and continuous development method.
- Created Restful web administrations utilizing Spring Boot and protected them with OAuth2.0.
- Monitored RESTful APIs and extracted them using Splunk software. Decoupling non-business endpoints from BPM saved spark, 32% of monthly operation cost.

Software engineer

July 2018- Dec 2020

- Worked on developing data visualization tool for client. Developing REST APIs using python flask for fetching processed data from backend.
- Built a platform-independent tool using ElectronJS and ReactJS for envisioning ECU architectures.
- Integrated a highly customizable third-party diagramming library (yFiles) for a superior user experience.
- Actively worked with UX team to explore various open-source design libraries.
- Demonstrated expertise in translating the client specific needs into easy-tounderstand software solutions generating over 80K\$ in business.

Software intern

Jan 2018 – Jun 2018

- Functional role, partnered directly with management in B2B to Manage Electronic Data Interchange (EDI) with partners systems: requirement, design, deployment, testing, go live, Hypercare, incident resolution.
- Migrated a few European clients from TLI to OpenText enterprise management.
 Formalized Price catalogue, Orders, Order response, DESADV, Invoice, Sales report, Inventory report.
- Planned and coordinated actions between different actors: Ralph Lauren business, RL IT, third-party providers, customers and improve customer data captures.

Academic projects:

- Amrita store —as part of the academic semester in Django stack using HTML, CSS, Python and SQLite.
- Exam cell automation a web application for universities and students to collaborate and attend examinations online. Front-end was created using HTML, CSS, Angular JS, with bootstrap framework and backend using Java business tier.
- IOS Application development using XCode and Swift CoreLocation, UIKit.
 Beacon for accessible computing inside building hallways (InProgress), assisted using voice commands.

California, united states.

+1 316-927-8500

Nandhu1296@ymail.com

in linkedin.com/in/nandhu1296/

github.com/Nandhu1296

medium.com/@nandhu1296

nandhu1296.github.io/

Skills:

Python, Java, C++, Swift, Html5&Css, ReactJs, JavaScript, MongoDB, Continuous Integration &Continuous Development, Linux/Unix, SpringBoot, MySQL, Django, EDI, Non-EDI

Technologies:

GIT, Maven, IBM IIB, WebSphereMQ, VSCode, Jira, ServiceNow, XCode, UIKit, Splunk, OpenShift, Docker, AWS, Postman, AS400, Putty.

Concepts:

- Web Application design & development.
- Cloud microservices.
- Basic machine learning.
- Software development lifecycle.
- Team leadership & Supervision.
- Proficient troubleshooting.

Education:

MS in computer science Aug '21- May '23

Wichita state university GPA: 3.56/4.0

Coursework: Software structures, System design, Data structures and algorithms, Microservices. Graduate Teaching assistant for Advanced Software engineering.

B.S in Computer science July '14- May '18

Amrita University GPA: 3.1/4.0

Coursework: Software engineering, OOP, Web Development, OS. Student assistant(Web Developer) for students clinic.

Awards and Certifications:

- Python and IBM integration Bus (IBM IIB), Enterprise service bus (ESB) certified by Infosys.
- Java certified by NIIT-ORACLE.
- AWS, Docker certified by LCO.
- Best sport-person in volleyball.
- 4th place in school chess, '07 to '08.